Kevin M. Homan

18475 Cattail Spring Dr. Leesburg, VA 20176 703-282-6873 Homan13@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE OVERVIEW

Kevin possesses ten plus years of experience in Systems Administration and Engineering of enterprise environments. He has contributed to all stages of the project lifecycle from design, implementation, operations and maintenance and disposal as well as providing end user support. His expertise includes engineering design and maintenance of Linux/Unix, Windows and VMWare environments. Kevin is familiar with automation tools such as Kickstart, Yum, Puppet and Red Hat Satellite. Additionally, he also possesses experience in setting up and maintaining solutions using products such as Hadoop (Cloudera), Lucene, and various database environments (MySQL, Oracle, Postgres).

TECHNICAL DOMAIN AND FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE

- Linux/Unix Administration (Red Hat variants, Ubuntu and variants)
- Linux/Unix Engineering
- VMWare Administration
- Jira
- Scripting (Bash, Basic Python)
- Monitoring Tools (Nagios, New Relic)
- Proposals and Business Development
- Configuration Management Tools (Puppet, Basic Ansible)
- Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, Glacier, RDS, VPC, ELB, CloudFormation, Lambda)

EDUCATION

M.S., Systems Engineering, George Washington University, Washington, DC, 2012 B.S., Information Science and Technology, Penn State University, University Park, PA, 2004

CERTIFICATIONS AND TECHNOLOGY SPECIFIC TRAINING

- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator Associate, 2018
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, 2017
- AWS Certified Developer Associate, 2017
- Project Management Professional (PMP), 2013
- Security+ 2009
- Network+, 2009
- Information Assurance Methodologist (IAM), 2007

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Cloud Solutions Architect

Northrop-Grumman, January 2018 - Present

Cloud architect building out a new capability for the Northrop-Grumman Tactical Systems sector. This capability is the design, and build of a technology agnostic solution across on premises VMWare computing, and cloud environments including Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Microsoft's Azure environment. This work involves comparing products such as CloudFormation Red Hat's CloudForms and Hashicorp's Terraform to turn infrastructure into code and be able to rapidly deploy a full stack infrastructure environment (networking, compute and data) for our users in the cloud or on premises provider of their choice. Kevin is using YAML and JSON to write templates that codify our infrastructure and deploy it in our environments. Additionally he is deploying an Ansible Tower offering that will act as a configuration management repository for the offering.

Systems Integration Engineer Northrop-Grumman, March 2017 – Present

Integration engineer and configuration manager for the Continuous Diagnostics and Mitigation program tasked with integrating solutions to allow our customer to discover, and know what is on their networks at all time. As configuration manager, and in addition to system integration duties Kevin manages the change management process; chairing weekly Configuration Change Board meetings and providing accurate reporting and requirements so CDM end customers can make accurate and informed adjudication decisions. Additionally Kevin provides engineering support to the ongoing proposal effort for the next phase of CDM work. Kevin's support includes expanding the footprint of the CDM internal lab to bring in new tools that will integrate and expand the existing CDM solution set in the next phase of work. Kevin also participated in an Internal Research and Development (IRAD) effort based off the CDM program using open source alternatives such as Elastic Search, HBase and Flume and built in the AWS cloud. Kevin provided expertise in quickly standing up infrastructure and using cost savings features such as Lambda and EC2 scheduler. For his work Kevin was listed as one of the key resources on the intellectual property paperwork for the project as Northrop looks to productize this solution set.

Senior Systems Administrator (DevOps) REI Systems, January 2015 – February 2017

Lead Engineer/Administrator with responsibilities managing LAMP stack systems across various hosting environments working closely with Developers. Our team manages infrastructure locally in vSphere and environments externally hosted by hosting partners and also within AWS and Rackspace. In addition to managing my team and handling day to day operational duties I participate in proposal work and actively research and recommend new technologies. As part of our work we have integrated products into our environment such as Jenkins, GitHub (migrating from Subversion) and New Relic application performance monitoring tools. We are actively growing our AWS presence and attempting to integrate more of its automated deployment and management tools as we learn and get comfortable with these technologies.

Lead Linux Engineer, US Government Customer Navstar Inc., October 2013-October 2014

As the Lead Linux Engineer for a US Government Customer I was responsible for managing a team of Linux Engineers/Administrators with responsibility for design, implementation and operations and maintenance of a Linux enterprise. Responsible for engineering studies, security configuration, and documentation as part of an effort to standardize his customer's environment on one Red Hat image. Led the effort to move enterprise Linux operations away from largely manual procedures to automated procedures using technology such as Kickstart, Yum, Puppet and Red Hat Satellite. My team performed an engineering study, drafted a report and briefed their Government Branch Chief on their plan and received authorization to proceed with a phased implementation. Additionally he managed the technical aspects of a small enclave-computing environment that was awarded a Unit Meritorious Citation from the Directorate Level.

Systems Engineer, US Government Customer Navstar Inc., October 2012-October 2013

As a Systems Engineer for a US Government Customer Mr. Homan supported a mixed Linux/Windows environment of about 100 servers. Mr. Homan supported daily administration of Red Hat variant Linux servers, Solaris as well as Windows 2008 Server instances that supported the customers various web applications. Additionally he led engineering and integration efforts for Microsoft's Windows System Update Service (WSUS), Kickstart services for Linux automated builds and McAfee's ePolicy Orchestrator (ePO) to assist his customer in automating common administration tasks. Additionally he provided a customer requested Concept of Operations on recapitalizing data center space for use as a technology-testing environment.

Systems Engineer, Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA) ORION Program Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC) April 2010-October 2012

As a Systems Engineer, Mr. Homan lead a team of five SAIC engineers on Integration efforts of DIA's ORION High Performance Compute Environment (HPCE), which was the Agency first private cloud/"Big Data" environment. Additionally he had to manage several sub-contractors who provided integration efforts as well as manage and be the company's representative to the various Vendors being integrated within the system. Mr. Homan was a direct report to the Senior Engineering staff and was responsible for drafting Change Requests and presenting them to Program Management, Security in addition to Senior Engineering staff when changes in configuration were required. Mr. Homan's work and management resulted in the initial system being delivered to the customer meeting the Initial Operating Capacity (IOC) deadline as well as the test bed system being awarded the "Showcase of Technology" at the DoDIIS Worldwide 2012 Conference.

Junior Systems Engineer, National Geospatial Intelligence Agency (NGA) Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC), April 2008-April 2010

Participated as a member of a 20 person engineering team providing engineering design, and operations and maintenance support to his customer's video and network backbone. Mr. Homan participated in design efforts and went on site to build out solutions as part of a large recapitalization effort to integrate new technologies into his customer's spaces. Additionally he spent time on-site supporting the analysts and their systems as an on-site administrator.

Information Assurance Analyst, United States Forrest Service and Department of Veterans Affairs EmeSec Inc., August 2006-April 2008

Performed verification and validation support activities to the United States Forrest Service and Department of Veterans Affairs for their respective Offices of the Chief Information Officer (CIO) looking at information technology Information Assurance requirements. Review focused on National Institute of Science and Technology (NIST) and Federal Information Security Management Act (FISMA) standards. Mr. Homan worked closely with senior IT staff reviewing current policy and procedure and making recommendations on changes to put his customers within NIST and FISMA compliance. Additionally he supported the training team by attending, and providing expertise during training sessions for Agency staff.

Loan Officers Assistant

CTX Mortgage Company, May 2006-June 2006

Mr. Homan worked with CTX customers managing their prequalification process following Federal Personally Identifiable Information (PII) requirements for the home loan process.

Production Supervisor

NV Homes, June 2004-April 2006

Managed and supervised multiple housing communities throughout the production life cycle. Managed sub-contractors, invoicing and billing and the building schedule.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Project Management Institute